<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>System Design on Yuxin Fan</title>
    <link>https://yx-fan.github.io/tags/system-design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in System Design on Yuxin Fan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://yx-fan.github.io/tags/system-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>MCP Orchestration System: Production-Oriented Agent Control Plane</title>
      <link>https://yx-fan.github.io/projects/mcp-orchestration-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yx-fan.github.io/projects/mcp-orchestration-system/</guid>
      <description>A production-oriented MCP (Model Control Plane) orchestration system designed to manage agentic workflows with statefulness, extensibility, cost control, and multi-step reasoning capabilities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building a Production-Oriented Semantic Search System with Milvus and Cross-Encoder Reranking</title>
      <link>https://yx-fan.github.io/projects/semantic-search-system-milvus-reranking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yx-fan.github.io/projects/semantic-search-system-milvus-reranking/</guid>
      <description>A production-ready semantic search system that separates recall and precision through a multi-stage retrieval pipeline. Combines Milvus vector search, distance-based filtering, and Cross-Encoder reranking for high-quality retrieval results.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Distributed Lock vs Row Lock vs Transaction</title>
      <link>https://yx-fan.github.io/log/distributed-lock-vs-row-lock-vs-transaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yx-fan.github.io/log/distributed-lock-vs-row-lock-vs-transaction/</guid>
      <description>These three mechanisms solve different problems at different layers: distributed locks protect business execution, row locks protect data mutation, and transactions define lock scope and atomicity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Redis Sorted Sets for Recent User Search History</title>
      <link>https://yx-fan.github.io/log/redis-sorted-sets-recent-search-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yx-fan.github.io/log/redis-sorted-sets-recent-search-history/</guid>
      <description>Treat recent search history as ephemeral user behavior, not core business data. Redis Sorted Sets provide a natural fit: O(log N) writes, automatic ordering, de-duplication, and bounded size—all without turning a lightweight behavior signal into a database concern.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Node.js Achieves High Concurrency on a Single CPU Core</title>
      <link>https://yx-fan.github.io/log/how-nodejs-achieves-high-concurrency/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yx-fan.github.io/log/how-nodejs-achieves-high-concurrency/</guid>
      <description>Node.js achieves high concurrency not by multi-threading, but through its event-driven, non-blocking I/O model. It efficiently overlaps I/O waiting time across requests, allowing a single thread to handle thousands of connections.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why OpenSearch Shouldn&#39;t Be Used as a Primary Database</title>
      <link>https://yx-fan.github.io/log/opensearch-shouldnt-be-primary-database/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yx-fan.github.io/log/opensearch-shouldnt-be-primary-database/</guid>
      <description>OpenSearch is built for search, not for storage. Its architecture prioritizes high-performance retrieval and aggregation, not transactional integrity or consistency.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Group Chat Architecture and Implementation</title>
      <link>https://yx-fan.github.io/projects/chat-group-core/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yx-fan.github.io/projects/chat-group-core/</guid>
      <description>An in-depth exploration of the architecture and implementation of a group chat system, covering group creation, subscription, real-time messaging, and gRPC-based communication between microservices.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-to-One Chat Architecture and Implementation</title>
      <link>https://yx-fan.github.io/projects/chat-one-to-one-core/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yx-fan.github.io/projects/chat-one-to-one-core/</guid>
      <description>An in-depth look into the one-to-one chat architecture and its implementation for handling text and media messages.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Travel Expense Tracker Backend System</title>
      <link>https://yx-fan.github.io/projects/travel-expense-tracker-backend-system-core/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yx-fan.github.io/projects/travel-expense-tracker-backend-system-core/</guid>
      <description>A modular backend system for managing travel expenses, built with Node.js and Express, featuring microservices, message queues, and integration with third-party APIs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CoolChat Platform System Design: Scalable and Secure Chat Architecture</title>
      <link>https://yx-fan.github.io/projects/chat-platform-system-design-core-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yx-fan.github.io/projects/chat-platform-system-design-core-project/</guid>
      <description>A scalable, real-time chat platform leveraging Web3 authentication, microservices architecture, and message queuing for high concurrency and performance.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
